<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Letters on Tony Klausing</title>
    <link>/categories/letters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Letters on Tony Klausing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/letters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter on tokenization</title>
      <link>/posts/letter_on_tokenization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/letter_on_tokenization/</guid>
      <description>The promise of tokenization is a exciting prospect in the blockchain space. Organizations such as the DAO and various ICOs highlight the trend, having enjoyed eye-poppingly large funding rounds on dubious credentials. We may tsk-tsk this speculation, but ICOs foretell what truly global and unfettered capital markets will look like &amp;hellip; then it&amp;rsquo;s pretty awesome. From the seeds of speculation, may great ideas and products flourish! And the beneficiaries of a half-trillion dollar crypto windfall can send their bits to whomever they please.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wallace Stevens, the Poet Laureate of Bitcoin</title>
      <link>/posts/poet_laureate_of_bitcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/poet_laureate_of_bitcoin/</guid>
      <description>Should there be a Poet Laureate of Bitcoin, the great modernist Wallace Stevens of Hartford, Connecticut, USA (1877-1955) would surely be a top candidate. For those who will say that cryptography isn&amp;rsquo;t enough alike poetry to warrant an official poet of it, channel your inner poet for moment and let your imagination roam &amp;hellip;
Because, you see, Mr. Stevens was a special case. He was at once astonishingly imaginative and disciplined and practical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Sports</title>
      <link>/posts/no_sports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/no_sports/</guid>
      <description>I remember some years ago meeting a programmer who made a remark about how different a world we would have if there weren&amp;rsquo;t any sports. &amp;ldquo;Imagine what we could accomplish when we used the money and energy from sports in more important areas like health and education,&amp;rdquo; he said.
I objected to his premise, arguing that sports was innately human. I had in mind the thought that if a world without sports and games existed, then a world without humans must be such a conclusion&amp;rsquo;s distopian prerequisite.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>