<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tony Klausing</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tony Klausing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Wallace Stevens, the Poet Laureate of Bitcoin</title>
      <link>/posts/poet_laureate_of_bitcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/poet_laureate_of_bitcoin/</guid>
      <description>Should there be a Poet Laureate of Bitcoin, the great modernist Wallace Stevens of Hartford, Connecticut, USA (1877-1955) would surely be a top candidate. For those who will say that cryptography isn&amp;rsquo;t enough alike poetry to warrant an official poet of it, channel your inner poet for moment and let your imagination roam &amp;hellip;
Because, you see, Mr. Stevens was a special case. He was at once astonishingly imaginative and disciplined and practical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Sports</title>
      <link>/posts/no_sports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/no_sports/</guid>
      <description>I remember some years ago meeting a programmer who made a remark about how different a world we would have if there weren&amp;rsquo;t any sports. &amp;ldquo;Imagine what we could accomplish when we used the money and energy from sports in more important areas like health and education,&amp;rdquo; he said.
I objected to his premise, arguing that sports was innately human. I had in mind the thought that if a world without sports and games existed, then a world without humans must be such a conclusion&amp;rsquo;s distopian prerequisite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Fallacy of Paper Clip Maximizing-Robots and Supergoals</title>
      <link>/posts/on_bostrom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/on_bostrom/</guid>
      <description>I take issue here with the notion of presentient and nearly deific artificial intelligences who shall, it is supposed, be programmed to achieve at all costs a &amp;ldquo;supergoal&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; only later to wreak accidental havoc on their hapless human inventors.
Consider a specific incarnation of the idea: the meme of the paper clip-maximizing super AI, popularized by Oxford University&amp;rsquo;s Prof. Nick Bostrom. It &amp;ldquo;seems perfectly possible,&amp;rdquo; writes Bostrom, &amp;ldquo;to have a superintelligence whose sole goal is something completely arbitrary, such as to manufacture as many paperclips as possible, and who would resist with all its might any attempt to alter this goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good evening, and welcome</title>
      <link>/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Dear reader,
Thanks for visiting my blog and welcome. I plan to write about economic history, art, the history of ideas, crypto systems, and whatever else comes to mind. Feel free to contact me @tonklaus.
Special thanks to the author of this useful tutorial about creating websites with Hugo, a Go app that generates static websites like this one.
Cheers, Tony</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>